Finding Aid for the Doris Fleming Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Doris Fleming Papers
2009
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0692
5.46 linear feet
Biographical Note
Doris Sigrid Anundsen Fleming was born in London, Ontario, Canada on January 3, 1901, to Emily Brock Anundsen and Alfred Anundsen. She came to the United States in 1922 to study voice with William S. Brady in New York City. She continued her studies there until she married Denna Frank Fleming on June 29, 1929 and came to Nashville, where her husband was a distinquished professor of Political Science and International Relations at Vanderbilt University.
Mrs. Fleming’s life long interest in music was realized in the several music clubs in Nashville of which she was a member: the Woman’s Musicale, the Wednesday Music Coterie, and the Musical Alumnae. She was also a member of the Vanderbilt Woman’s Club and of Shandygaff.
Doris Fleming was a lifetime aide to her husband in the preparation of his many books and scholarly articles and publications, and together they supported the work of the American Friends Service Committee, the United Nations Association of Nashville, and of other service and scholarship organizations. Professor Fleming’s papers are also held in Vanderbilt University Special Collections and University Archives.
In addition to her musical activities, Doris Fleming studied painting under Gus Baker in Nashville and with instructors in Palo Alto and Vancouver, British Columbia. She was a member of the United Church of Canada. After D.F. Fleming died, Doris Anundsen Fleming returned to Canada in 1985. She died in January 1990 at the age of 89.
Scope and Content Note
This collection of papers is contained in 13 Hollinger boxes and measures 5.42 linear feet.
The papers are comprised of personal and biographical materials that include genealogical research materials, legal documents and related correspondence, and photographs. The collection also includes Doris Fleming’s writings, mostly poems, written during the 1920’s when she lived in New York City. The Music Collection is the most significant series and is comprised of sheet music, programs, and notes on the music and songs represented in this collection. Of interest are a number of songs by Scandinavian composers, including Edvard Grieg, Arne Dorumsgaard, Armas Jarnefelt, Erkki Melartin, and Jean Sibelius among others. There is also a small collection of songs by the 20th century French composer Francis Poulenc.
Other series include subject research on Canada and Separatism, and a collection of travel materials for visits to Norway, India, Great Britain and other places.
- Correspondence – Outgoing and Incoming
  - Outgoing and incoming - general (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Incoming – family (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Personal and Biographical
  - Biographical note; gift to Eastern Illinois University by Mrs. Fleming; Gift to Volunteer Community College; “Instructions upon my death”; “If I die in Nashville, Memorial service for Doris A. Fleming”; “List of Furniture and articles from home in London, Ontario, Canada” (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Birthday and Invitation cards (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1928 yearbook International House – Photo of Doris Anundsen on page 11 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Genealogical materials - Norway (1) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Genealogical materials - Norway (2) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Genealogical materials - Norway (3) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Genealogical materials - Norway (4) (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Genealogical materials - Norway (5) (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Genealogical materials - Norway (6) (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Legal documents and related correspondence (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Legal documents and related correspondence (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Legal documents - Power of Attorney, November 29, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Legal documents - Real Estate contracts, October 21, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Documents for move to Canada in, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Photographs (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Writings - Poems - Typescripts
  - 1921 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - 1922 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - 1925 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - 1926 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - 1927 (1) (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - 1927 (2) (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - 1928 (1) (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - 1928 (2) (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Writings - Poems - Typescripts
  - 1929 (1) (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - 1929 (2) (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - 1930 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - 1931 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - 1933 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - 1951, 1953, 1957, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Undated (1) (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Undated (2) (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Undated (3) (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Undated (4) (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Collections - Early poems - “Some Verses for Mother” (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Poems - Verses written for Cathy and Johnny by Doris Fleming (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Poems, verses (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Writings - other
  - Short story - untitled (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - “An Alphabet of Definitions” (Holograph and typescript) (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Short story “Mrs. Robin: a Study” (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - “Institute for Advanced Study, 1946” (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Paper - “What was Cezanne’s Contribution to Modern Poetry? How was He Original? How Did He Differ from Impressionism?” for Art III Gus Baker, December 18, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Notes and Research for Paper on Cezanne, December 1957, Art III, Gus Baker (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - “There is a River: the Story of Edgar Cayce” from Thomas Sugrue’s book for the Shandygaff Program, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Paper on Edgar Cayce (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Paper on Edgar Cayce (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Paper on Edgar Cayce (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Notes and research for paper for Shandygaff program on reincarnation based on Gina Germinara’s “The World Within” (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Book review by Doris Fleming of The World Within by Gina Cerminara, Nashville Banner, February 8, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Notes and research (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Writings - by others
  - Important to Doris Fleming (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Important to Doris Fleming (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Important to Doris Fleming (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Poetry notebook of Eric Harold Anundsen, 1919 - 1929 (father of Doris Fleming) (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Poems by Eric Harold Anundsen (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Poems by Eric Harold Anundsen “ A Little Book of Fragments” Storm Wind” “In Careless Memory” “Taffy” (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Notes, articles, research (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Art the Image of the West, Julie Braun - Vogelstein, Pantheon, New York, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Subject Files – Quebec, Canada and Separatism
  - Correspondence and news articles (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Notes on the BNA Act, 1867 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - News articles, 1974, 1975, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - News articles, 1977, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - News articles, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - News articles (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - News articles (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Articles in MacLean’s, May 1, 1978; June 12, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Rene Levesque Interview from the MacNeil/Lehrer Report, January 25, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - “The French Speaking Population of Canada and the Future of Quebec” Nashville Committee on Foreign Relations, Wednesday, June 15, 1977, His Excellency M. Claude Morin (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence and notes for paper (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - How Are We Governed? By John Richer and John Saywell (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Newspaper Article in The Globe and Mail, June 3, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Music Collection – Sheet Music – Scandanavian Composers
  - Alfvens, Hugo “Waldesstille” (Skogen Sover) (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Dorumsgaard, Arne “Overland - Sanger” op. 5, no. 1, op.6, no. 1 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Grieg, Edvard “Beliebte Lieder “Zur Johannisnacht” (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Grieg, Edvard “Lyrische Stucke, op. 43 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Grieg, Edvard “Romancer og Sange” Bind I and II (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Grieg, Edvard “Romancer og Sange” Bind III and IV (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Grieg, Edvard “Romancer og Sange” Bind V and VI (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Grieg, Edvard “Romancer og Sange” Bind VII and VIII (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Grieg, Edvard “Romancer og Sange” Bind IX and X (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Grieg, Edvard “Solvejg’s Wiegenlied” (Solvejg’s Cradle Song); “Med en Vandlilje” (With a Water lily); “Vaaren” (Spring); “Det Synd”; “Ein Schwan” (a Swan) (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Grieg, Edvard “Weihnachts - Wiegenlied” (Yuletide Cradle Song) from Sechs Lieder; “Eros” from Beliebten Lieder; Vocal Album ( Vol. I, II, III, IV); “Ein Traum” (A Dream), op. 48, no. 6 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Hogsbro, Inga “Three Songs” 1. Mother’s Song 2. Too Late 3. Cradle Song (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Irgens - Jensen, Ludwig “Altar” ( Halldis Moren) (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Jarnefelt, Armas “Berceuse” (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Jordan, Sverre “Fire Sanger” op. 41; “U-aar” (Scarce Year) (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Kierulf, Halfdan “Romancer og Sange” (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Kilpinen, Yrjo “Lieder um den Tod” nach Gedichten von Christian Morgenstern, op. 62 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Lindberg, Oskar “Hur Skall Man Bruden Klada?” (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Melartin, Erkki “Three Runeberg Songs” No. 1 Consolation No. 2 Autumn Eve No. 3 The Briar (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Nordquists, Gustaf “Havtak” “Visa” “Kunde jag dikta en visa” (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Rangstrom, Ture “Fem Dikter - Melodie”; “Sex Visor” (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Tischendorf, Gabriel “Jeg vil vaerge mit Land” (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Music Collection - Sheet Music - Composers
  - Anonymous XVth Century (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Anundsen, Doris Sigrid “Late Autumn” (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Bach, J. S. “Songs and Airs” Book I for soprano (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Bach, J. S. “Songs and Airs” Book II for soprano (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Beethoven, Ludwig van “Wonne der Wehmuth” ( poem by Goethe); “Sonate Pathetique”, op. 13 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Berg, Alban “Sieben Fruhe Lieder” (1907); “Die Nachtigall”; Blech, Leo “Acht Liedchen” op. 21 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Brahms, Johannes Fifty Songs with Piano Accompaniment, 1910 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Brahms, Johannes “Four Scriptural Songs” op. 121 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Brahms, Johannes Sixty Selected Songs (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Cornelius, Peter “Six Christmas Songs” (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Debussy, Claude “Fetes Galantes”; “Ariettes oubliees” (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Debussy, Claude “ La Fille aux Cheveux de Lin”; “L’enfant Prodigue” (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Debussy, Claude “L’Enfant Prodigue” (Scene Lyrique ) (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Faure, Gabriel La Bonne Chanson 9 Melodies pour une voix avec accompaniment de piano (Poesies de Paul Verlaine) (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Faure, Gabriel Vingt Melodies, chant et piano (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Fickenscher, Arthur “Where go the Boats” (words by Robert Louis Stevenson) (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Graener, Paul “Funf Lieder” op. 49 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Handel, George Frederick selections from Julius Caesar, Semele, and Xerxes (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Haydn, Franz Josef “She Never Told her Love” (words by Shakespeare) (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Hindemith, Paul “Das Marien Leben” (poem by Rainer Maria Rilke) (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Music Collection – Sheet Music – Composers
  - Lehman, Liza In a Persian Garden - A Song Cycle for Four Solo Voices (the words selected from The Rubaiyat of Omar Khayyam) (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Loewe, Carl “Niemand hat’s gesehen” ( No one saw at all) (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Mahler, Gustav “Eight Songs” (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Mahler, Gustav Kindertotenlieder (Songs on the Death of Infants) for voice and piano (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Mahler, Gustav “Lieder and Gesange”; “Lieder Eines Fahrenden Gesellen” (Songs of a Wayfarer) “Um Mitternacht” (At Midnight) (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Mahler, Gustav The Song of the Earth,( vocal score) (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Malotte, Albert Hay “The Lord’s Prayer” (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Marx, Joseph “The Elves”; “Song to St. Mary”; “Wanderers Nacht Lied” (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Marx, Joseph Lieder und Gesange - “Bacarolle””Der Ton” “Windrader” (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Marx, Joseph Lieder - Album, II, III; Wanderer’s Night Song ( Goethe) (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Metcalf, John “Absent” words by Catherine Young Glen (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Mozart, W. A. “Alleluja” (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Nevin, Ethelbert “Love Song” (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Poldowski, M. “L’Heure Exquise” (Tempting Hour) (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Poulenc, Francis “Banalities” “Calligrammes” “Montparnasse, Hyde Park” poems by Guillaume Apollinaire (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Poulenc, Francis “Cinq Poems” de Max Jacob (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Poulenc, Francis Cocardes, Chansons Populaire sur des poems de Jean Cocteau 1, Miel de Narbonne 2. Bonne d’enfant 3. Enfant de Troupe (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Poulenc, Francis Trois Poemes de Louise Lalanne 1. Le Present 2. Chanson 3. Hier; Fiancailles pour Rire Six Melodies sur des poems de Louise de Vilmorin; Metamorphoses poems de Louise de Vilmorin (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Poulenc, Francis “Le pont un Poeme”l “La Grenouillere”; “Le Dromadaire” from “Le Bestiare”; “Le Chevre du Thibet” et al. poemes de Guillaume Apollinaire (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Poulenc, Francis Cinq Poemes de Paul Eluard; “ Rod euse au Front de Verre ”; Tel Jour Telle Nuit, Neuf Melodies sur les Poemes de Paul Eluard (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Poulenc, Francis Airs Chantes s’apres des poemes de Jean Moreas 1. Air Romantique 2. Aire Champetre 3. Aire Grave 4. Air Vif (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Poulenc, Francis Melodies; “Nous voulons une Petite Soeur” (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Poulenc, Francis “Trois Chansons de F. Garcia - Lorca”; “Songs for Children” (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Poulenc, Francis - Notes on Songs (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Poulenc, Francis - Lists of Songs (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Poulenc, Francis - Biographical information and list of complete works (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Poulenc, Francis - N.Y. Times article “Chat with Poulenc” November 7, 1948] (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Reger, Max “Maria Wieggenlied”; “Traume, Traume, Du Mein Susses Leben” (Box 6, Folder 28)
- Music Collection - Sheet Music - Composers
  - Rogers, James H. “Songs - The Star” (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Saint-Saens, Camille “Le Cygne” (the Swan from the Carnival of the Animals) (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Schumann, Robert “Samtliche Lieder fur eine Singsstimme mit Klavierbegleitung” Band I. (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Schumann, Robert “Fruhlingsnacht”; “Volksliedchen”; “Erstes Grun” (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Schumann, Robert “Samtliche Lieder” Band I. (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Schumann, Robert “Silent Tears” (Stille Thranen) op. 35, no. 10 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Sibelius, Jean “Black Roses”; “The First Kiss” (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Stenson, Ervine J. “ The Prayer Perfect” (poem by James Whitcomb Riley) (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Strauss, Richard “ 4 Lieder” op. 27; “Sechs Lieder,” op. 37 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Strauss, Richard “5 Lieder,” op. 48; “Freundliche Vision,” op. 48, no. 1; “Kling” op. 48, no. 3 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Strauss, Richard “Sechs Lieder,” op. 68; “Ruhe, meine Seele,” op. 27, no. 1 (Rest Thee, My Spirit) (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Strauss, Richard “Funf Lieder”; “Heimliche Aufforderung (The Lover’s Pledge), op. 27, no. 3; “Acht Gedichte” (Die Georgine) (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Strauss, Richard “Six Songs” (In German and English) (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Taylor, Deems “Waters Ripple and Flow” (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Tours, Berthold “Complete Instructor for the Violin” (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Trunk, Richard “Fruhlingssonne” op. 9, no. 3; “Weihestunde” op. 11, no. 1; “Komm!”, op. 11, no. 3; Auf der Brucke, op. 21, no. 1; “Die Nachtsgallen” op. 21, no. 3 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Trunk, Richard Lieder II; “ On My Native Village” (In Meiner Heimat), op. 14, no. 2 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Trunk, Richard “Weihnachtslieder” op. 61, no. 2; “Heitere Lieder, “ op. 63, no. 1 - 4 (Box 7, Folder 18)
- Music Collection - Sheet Music - Composers
  - Wolf, Hugo Ausgewahlte Lieder Fur Eine Singstimme und Klavier (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Wolf, Hugo “Elfen” (lied); “Mignon” (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Wolf, Hugo “Er Ist” (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Wolf, Hugo The Favorite Songs and Ballads of Hugo Wolf, 1860 - 1903 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Wolf, Hugo Fifty Songs (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Wolf, Hugo Gedichte von Goethe Fur Eine Singstimme und Klavier, Band I (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Wolf, Hugo Songs on Poems by Goethe (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Wolf, Hugo Songs on Italian Lyrics for Voice and Piano, vol. I and III (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Wolf, Hugo Songs on Poems by Eichendorff for Voice and Piano, Vol. I; Songs on Miscellaneous Poetry for Voice and Piano, Vol. 1 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Wolf, Hugo Songs on Poems by Moericke for Voice and Piano, Vol. II and Vol. IV (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Wolf, Hugo “Gedichte von Eduar Morike fur eine Singstimme und Klavier” Rubenstein, A. “Voices of the Woods” Sibelius, Jean “Valse Triste” (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Wolff, Erich J. “Alle Dinge haben Sprache” op. 19, no. 2 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Art Songs for the Modern Repertoire ( representing composers of fifteen nationalities) (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Folksongs; Songs by European Composers (Box 8, Folder 14)
- Music Collection - Sheet Music - Song Collections
  - Modern Scandanavian Songs, Volume I, Alfven to Kjerulf (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Songs of Sweden - Eighty-Seven Swedish Folk and Popular Songs (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - My Favorite German Songs - Elena Gerhardt (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Maggie Teyte Album of French Song (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Anthology of Modern French Song, a Collection of Thirty-nine Songs with Piano Accompaniment (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Additional Exercises to Richter’s Manual of Harmony by Alfred Richter (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous - handwritten (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Fragments (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Songs unidentified (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Composition paper (Box 9, Folder 10)
- Music Collection – Sheet Music - Programs
  - Alda, Frances in Carnegie Hall, NYC, December 11, 1927 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Averino, Olga at the Town Hall, NYC, November 27, 1938 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Bernac, Pierre and Poulenc, Francis in Town Hall, NYC, November 7, 1948; November 20, 1948, February 24, 1950 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Bjoerling, Jussi in Town Hall, NYC, January 4, 1938 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Boston Symphony Orchestra (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Brahms, Johannes and Schumann, Robert - translations of songs (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Branzell, Karin in Town Hall, NYC, January 5, 1947 and December 5, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - De Luca, Giuseppe in Town Hall, NYC, November 6, 1947 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Faulkner, Keith in Ward - Belmont Auditorium, March 22, 1938 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Flagstad, Kirsten in Carnegie Hall, March 6, 1938; December 22, 1947; January 3, 1948; with newspaper review (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Fleming, Doris A. Christmas Music Girls Glee Club of Vanderbilt University, December 10, 1933 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Fleming, Doris A., 1934, 1935, 1936 programs with notes and newspaper articles (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Fleming, Doria Anundsen at First Methodist Episcopal Church, May 3, 1935 with program notes on the songs (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Frijsh, Povla in Theresa L. Kaufman Auditorium, NYC, January 9, 1938 with composer and program notes (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Garrison, Mabel at the Guild Theatre, December 18, ????, Text of Songs (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Gerhardt, Elena in Town Hall, NYC (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Hackett, Arthur in Town Hall, NYC, January 5, 1929 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Lehmann, Lotte in Town Hall, NYC, October 18, 1938; January 7, 1942; February 15, 1948; February 29, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Lehmann, Lotte in Town Hall, NYC, January 19, 1947; February 20, 1949; March 3, 1949 with newspaper review (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Lehmann, Lotte in Town Hall, NYC, January 26, 1947; February 22, 1948; in McMillin Academic Theater of Columbia University in NYC (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Morrisey, Marie - Recital English Texts (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Olszewska, Maria in Town Hall, NYC, March 5, ???? (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Onegin, Sigrid - Recital program notes (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Peters, Julia in Town Hall NYC, October 18, 1933 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Rethberg, Elisabeth in Town Hall, NYC, December 8, 1935 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Riverside Church, NYC, October 9, 1938 includes ministry of music (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Schiotz, Aksel in Town Hall, NYC, December 1, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Schwarzkopf, Elisabeth and Parsons, Geoffrey in Royal Festival Hall, May 6, 1967 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Serkin, Rudolf, and Wettergren, Gertrud in Town Hall, NYC, January 5, 1938 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Tarver, Helen at Milwaukee - Downer College, November 16, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - Teyte, Maggie in Town Hall, NYC, October 23, 1946; November 20, 1946; December 11, 1946 (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Teyte, Maggie in Town Hall, NYC, January 15, 1948; March 11, 1948; at Princeton University Concerts, January 8, 1949 (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - Thomas, John Charles in Carnegie Hall, November 23, 1938 (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - Tourel, Jennie in Town Hall NYC, March 13, 1949 (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - Watson, Jean in Carnegie Hall, December 12, 1947 (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - Wolfe, Laurence in Town Hall, NYC, October 24, 1928 (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - Wolff, Ernst “Lieder Recital”, November 22, 1940 (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - The Bagby Music Lover’s Foundation - 1940, 1941; “Charles Martin Loeffler” (Box 10, Folder 38)
  - “Goethe Bi-Centenary” in the Pabst Theater, Milwaukee, Wisconsin, March 16, 1949 (Box 10, Folder 39)
  - Promenade Concerts conducted by Sir Henry J. Wood, 1938 (Box 10, Folder 40)
  - Notes on Songs (Box 10, Folder 41)
  - Notes on Songs (Box 10, Folder 42)
  - Notes on Songs (Box 10, Folder 43)
  - Notes on Songs (Box 10, Folder 44)
  - Notebook of Doris Anundsen - Words and music to “A Prayer” (Box 10, Folder 45)
  - Music Notebook of Doris Anundsen (Box 10, Folder 46)
- Music Collection – Publications
  - Pamphlet - “The English School of Lutenist Song Writers” (Box 10, Folder 47)
  - Schirmer’s Course in Contemporary Musical Biography; Charles Tomlinson Griffes; Gabriele Sibella (Box 10, Folder 48)
  - Text Book of Songs (in repertoire of Feodor Chaliapin), 1921 (Box 10, Folder 49)
  - Elson’s Pocket Music Dictionary, 1909 (Box 10, Folder 50)
- Music Collection - Publications
  - Fillebrown, Thomas Resonance in Singing and Speaking (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - The Emperor Jones (English libretto), music by Louis Gruenberg, 1932, after Eugene O’Neill’s play; “Campaign to Save Metropolitan Opera” New York, February 23, 1933 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Music Dictation Books, 1930 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - News articles (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Articles “New American Operas” (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Articles on vocal recitals, New York Times, February 24, 1952 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - “Music of the Post - Wagner Period” with accompanying newspaper articles on Berg, Schoenberg, Lizst, and Wolf from New York Times, (1950’s) (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Articles - Armstrong, William G. “Singing Builds Character” in The Etude Music Magazine, February 1948 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Articles “Leading Motives of the Ring of the Nibelung” (Box 11, Folder 9)
- Sketchbooks (some with notes)
  - Sketchbook with notes (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Sketchbook with notes (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Sketchbook with notes (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Sketchbook with notes (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Sketchbook with notes (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Sketchbook with notes (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Sketchbook with notes (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Sketchbook with notes (Box 11, Folder 17)
- Travel Materials
  - AAA Planning Map of Europe; Map of Stockholm; “Stockholm Capital of Sweden” “See Norway and Scandanavia” (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Canada, Vancouver – brochure (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - France, Reims - La Ville - Album Artistique - Edition Speciale des Amis de la Cathedrale (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Germany, Berlin and Worms am Rhein photograph albums; postcard from Warszawa (Box 12, Folder 4)